<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="catsymptoms1"><![CDATA[
        <h3>Cancer: </h3>
        <p>Cancer is a “multifactorial” disease, which means it has no known single cause.
            Squamous cell carcinoma of the ear, eyelid or nose is a skin cancer caused by repeated exposure to the sun.
            Lymphosarcoma or lymphoma (LSA), is one of the most common type of cancer in cats. Some reports estimate that 30% of all reported cat cancers are due to LSA.
        </p>
        <b>Symptoms: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">Lumps </li>
            <li>Swelling</li>
            <li>Persistent sores or skin infections, scaly and/or red skin patches</li>
            <li>Abnormal discharge from any part of the body</li>
            <li>Bad breath, difficulty breathing, urinating or defecating</li>
            <li>Weight loss, decreased or loss of appetite</li>
            <li>Sudden lameness, change in behavior</li>
            <li>Diarrhea or vomiting</li>
        </ul>
        <b>Prevention: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">Keeping your cat indoors will protect her from certain skin cancers caused by repeated sun exposure and sunburn.</li>
            <li>Breast cancer is a common cancer for cats, but it can be avoided by having your cat spayed before her first heat cycle.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>Treatment: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">Common treatments include surgery, chemotherapy, radiation and immunotherapy or a combination of therapies.</li>
            <li>Good nutrition and loving care can greatly enhance your cat’s quality of life.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></string>
    <string name="catsymptoms2"><![CDATA[
        <h3>Feline Leukemia Virus (FelV): </h3>
        <p>First discovered in the 1960s, feline leukemia virus is a transmittable RNA retrovirus that can severely inhibit a cat’s immune system.
            It is one of the most commonly diagnosed causes of disease and death in domestic cats. Because the virus doesn’t always manifest symptoms right away,
            any new cat entering a household—and any sick cat—should be tested for FeLV.</p>
        <b>Symptoms: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">Loss of appetite and weight loss, changes in behavior, lethargy</li>
            <li>Pale or inflamed gums, poor coat condition</li>
            <li>Respiratory distress, upper respiratory infections</li>
            <li>Vision or other eye problems</li>
            <li>Chronic skin disease, seizures</li>
            <li>Diarrhea and vomiting, jaundice</li>
        </ul>
        <b>Prevention: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">There is a vaccine available for cats who are at risk of contracting FeLV. Like all vaccines,
                there are risks involved in vaccination, and the vaccine is not a 100% guarantee against infection.</li>
            <li>As with any infectious disease, the best prevention is eliminating sources of exposure.
                Routine FeLV testing and keeping your cat indoors and away from cats whose FeLV status is not known remain the best way to prevent your cat from becoming infected.</li>
        </ul>

        <b>Treatment: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">Feed your cat a nutritionally balanced diet, one free of raw meat, eggs and unpasteurized dairy products.</li>
            <li>Provide a quiet place for your cat to rest indoors and away from other cats who could promote disease.</li>
            <li>Sadly there is no cure for FeLV, and it is estimated that less than 20% of clinically infected cats survive more than three years of active infection.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></string>
    <string name="catsymptoms3"><![CDATA[
        <h3>Rabies: </h3>
        <p>Rabies is a viral disease that affects the brain and spinal cord of all mammals, including cats, dogs and humans. This preventable disease has been reported in every state except Hawaii.
            There’s good reason that the very word “rabies” evokes fear in people—once symptoms appear, rabies is close to 100% fatal.</p>
        <b>Symptoms: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">Changes in behavior (including aggression, restlessness and lethargy)</li>
            <li>Increased vocalization</li>
            <li>Loss of appetite</li>
            <li>Weakness</li>
            <li>Disorientation</li>
            <li>Paralysis</li>
            <li>Seizures</li>
            <li>Sudden death</li>
        </ul>
        <b>Prevention: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">Vaccination is the key.</li>
            <li>Vaccinating your cat doesn\'t just protect her from rabies—it also protects your cat if she bites someone.</li>
        </ul>
        <b>Treatment: </b>
        <ul>
            <li style="margin-top: -10px;">The direct fluorescent antibody test is the most accurate test for diagnosis, but it can only be performed after the death of the animal.</li>
            <li>There is no treatment or cure for rabies once symptoms appear. The disease results in fatality.</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></string>
</resources>